I'm a highly motivated, pro-active web developer & engineering Steve Jenkins

manager specializing in large web applications. With 10+ years Email: resume@skysteve.com

post university experience in fast paced start up companies in the DOB: 1990-02-14 UK and Canada. Currently living Squamish, BC, Canada as a Nationality: Canadian

citizen.

# Areas of expertise/Skills

Frontend Backend General

TypeScript Node.js Team Leadership
Javascript NextJS Mentoring & career

ES2015/ES2016 (ES6+) AWS development

React/Redux AWS CDK/Cloudformation Product brief creation
Angular Docker Technical Design
Object Orientated Redis documentation

Jasmine/mocha/chai unit tests Mongodb Scoping and ticket breakdown
Service Workers Express JS Scrum/Agile/Scrum master

CSS(3) (inc responsive) PostgreSQL Analytical evaluation

HTML(5) Rabbit MQ Continuous deployment (CI/CD)
Web components (Native & Github Actions/Circle CI Build Systems (Webpack, rollup)

React) Problem solving

# **Experience**

### Durable

October 2023 - February 2024

Technical lead/software engineer

Primarily responsible for the CRM Module including a rebuild of the old code

Implemented internationalization across the website builder including laying foundations for further development

Built new website blocks for the website builder

Added additional functionality to existing modules including migrations to new data structures.

Helped to guide and implement a new sprint process.

Helped to guide and implement a new sprint process

Worked closely with customer service to address issues as well as identify themes and escalate these with solutions/plans

Investigated, scoped and developed a proof of concept for scheduling

### Technology used

React, NextJS, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Vercel

# Tile/Life360 (Originally Tile, Acquired by Life360)

September 2020 - September 2023

Team Lead/manager for a team of at most 13 developers across tile.com and life360.com

Work with HR and management to best support the team during an acquisition of Tile by Life360

Management responsibilities include 1-1s with team, performance reviews and career development

Managing the team through company layoffs including loosing team members and key stakeholders

Tech lead for tile.com replatform from initial platform selection to site live including site architecture (e-commerce site)

AWS infrastructure as code (CDK) for new platform infrastructure

Launched replatform with no downtime and phased rollout across multiple locales and domains

Communicating with stakeholders and design to refine requirements

Scum master: Run sprint ceremony meetings (standups, planning, retrospectives, grooming)

Help coach members of the team and provide opportunities for them to challenge themselves and learn Setup and maintain monitoring and alerting for critical systems as well as participate in on-call rotor

Spoken at an in-person conference about Tile.com's replatform

### Technology used

React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, AWS (CDK, ECS, SQS, S3, EC2, Lambda, DynaomDB, CloudFormation, CloudFront), Cloudflare, Github Actions (CI/CD), Netlify, BigCommerce

### JungleScout October 2018 - August 2020

Team Lead for a team of 4 developers

Management responsibilities include 1-1s with team, performance reviews and career development

Product road mapping with product manager and design review meetings with PM & designers

Frontend specialist including knowledge sharing and mentoring all things Frontend

Implemented various new features and updates to existing features in React

Architected and implemented websockets to provide live updates

Helped to migrate a legacy application into our main codebase and support the maintenance

Instrumental in identifying tech debt and working with management and other teams to address it

Lead a standards and testing tribe across teams to drive forwards our standards

Updated our build process to enable code splitting and worked hard to reduce our bundle size

Rebuilt our alert emails to be mobile friendly and work across email platforms

Responsible for redesigning and delivering our developer onboarding sessions for new hires

Working with CI and AWS to improve our build and deployment processes

#### Technology used

React/Redux, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, AWS (ECS, SQS, S3, EC2, Lambda, DynaomDB, CloudFormation, CloudFront), Docker, CircleCl, Websockets, Ruby/Rails, SQL

#### SaleCycle March 2016 - September 2018

Helped to develop new data scraping script (written in TypeScript) for clients (support down to IE10)

Developed a new testing system for the above script using Puppeteer and Cucumber, and a build system to push scripts to S3

Helped to develop large, scaleable backend systems to process incoming data

Developed docker based microservices for multiple project with automated tests and continuous delivery Converted core JavaScript over to TypeScript

Helped to develop and manage AWS services including using AWS CloudFormation

Lead a project to replace an old legacy email compilation system with a new microservices solution utilizing ECS and SQS

Working as part of a cross continent team

Helping to train and develop other employees including in remote offices

Training an outsourced team in Belarus

Mentoring junior members of the team and assisting other teams

### Technology used

TypeScript, JavaScript, Node.js, AWS (ECS, SQS, S3, EC2, Lambda, DynaomDB, CloudFormation, CloudFront), Docker, React JS, CircleCl, Websockets, mocha, Puppeteer

#### Spontly October 2014 - March 2016

Architected and built an internal social media management tool to automate posts to facebook and twitter

Implemented vagrant boxes for most of the development and live environments

Implemented continuous integration build systems (including deployment)

Archeticted a web app version of existing android and ios apps using node JS and marionette

Developing and managing backend systems to generate data and process queues

Architected and developed most of a football based gambling game

Helping to mentor and manage interns

# Technology used

JavaScript, Node.js, AWS (SQS, S3, EC2), MongoDB, Backbone.js, Marionette.js, Vagrant, Code ship

# **CANDDi** 2012 - August 2014

Scrum master for a team of up to 4 running daily meetings, planning meetings, retrospectives and ensuring processes were followed

Responsible for embedded tracking JavaScript which records user actions and must be cross browser compliant (including IE6)

Created most of the node.js projects responsible for collecting inbound data, pushing live updated to users and the majority of our outbound email communications

Implemented most of the current CANDDi dashboard in Backbone.js and Marionette.js along with mustache templates

Developing and maintaining large sections of the canddi.com public website using jekyll and implementing Grunt.js to build the site to enable extra features

Managing time between planned sprint work and maintenance (bug fixes) work

Responsible for designing and scoping some large technical challenges such as implementing new features as well as taking part in group planning sessions when required

### Technology used

JavaScript, Node.js, AWS (SQS, S3, EC2), MongoDB, Backbone.js, Marionette.js, RabbitMQ

# Hewlett Packard (intern) 2010 - 2011

Internship between 2nd and 3rd year at university as part of the deduplication team in the disk to disk backup storage business

Largely a supporting role within the team although I did mange to implement some bug fixes in live code during my time

Responsible for setting up and managing a suite of test servers, code quality systems, performance testing, unit tests

Participated in agile (scrum) activities within a large team including planning and stand-up meetings

#### Manx Electricity Authority (Vacation work) between 2008 - 2010

General IT support and VB scripts to aid with monitoring and debugging

#### Education

# Newcastle University 2008 - 2012

BSc (Hons) Computing Science with Industrial Placement 1st Class honours

# Castle Rushen High School 2001 - 2008

A Levels: Computing, Physics, Chemistry, General Studies

GCSEs: 2As, 8Bs, 2Cs

# **Transferable skills**

Skilled in communicating technical concepts to non-technical people

Experience working with product and design teams to help refine ideas and scope projects

Working within both small and large teams as well as within a wider organization

Ability to adapt to new environments and systems

Ability to learn new programming languages and styles of working

Experience working within a distributed team and working remotely including across time zones

Experience mentoring junior team members and less technical members of staff

Strong foundation/background in Vanilla JavaScript inc ES6+

# Additional skills

Full, clean diving license (since age 16)
Paragliding pilot license and former coach

# **Personal Interests**

Paragliding, Kite surfing, Mountain Biking, Snowboarding, Rock Climbing, Skiing, Skydiving.